Next is the body.
How to place the front panel on the table.
Place the triangular thread markings on
the sleeve cap side right sides
together, overlapping left and right.
Through the fabric grain of the Katayama
cloth, secure a pin at
the edge of the ear.
Align the two selvedges on the back seam
side of both the front
and back panels neatly.
Place the ruler on the front piece
and lay the back piece on top of it.
When removing the Katayama ruler, gently
pull it out while applying slight pressure
to prevent the two halves from
shifting out of alignment.
I shall mark the sacred site's seal;
measure the right edge and the
centre—three points in
total—and it shall be complete.
Please note the dimensions including
an additional 2 centimetres at the hem.
The hem is trimmed and finished
with a continuous seam.
Please note the hem
allowance is 2 centimetres.
External 23cm.
Note: 15 cm body length.
Next, the width mark.
First, mark 1 cm seam allowances at
approximately 20 cm
intervals down to the hem.
The width mark is added from the seam
allowance, plus the back width
and 0.4 cm of seam allowance,
Mark from the hem to the side seam.
At this point, the back width is narrow,
and the difference between the
shoulder width and the back width is
For those over 3 centimetres, the
measurement shall be
taken to the collar base.
Record a shoulder width increase
of 0.4 centimetres at Katayama.
Tie the katayama and
miyatsuguchi diagonally.
Mark the mountain fold on
the sleeve attachment side.
Next, mark a 9-centimetre collar opening
on the back piece, 2 centimetres
behind the side seam from Katayama.
At the break of dawn,
I set my waiting pins.
I will.
Do not cut all the way to the front panel.
Insert cardboard between
the front and back panels.
Insert the scissors.
At this point, take care
not to cut too much.
This completes the marking
for the back panel.
Next, lift the two pieces of fabric for
the back panel to reveal the front panel.
Reapply the side and hem markings
securely, ensuring they
align with the back panel.
Mark 23 centimetres on the side
where the lapel is attached.
At this position, mark 8 centimetres from
the right edge for those with a thick
chest and 9 centimetres
for those who are slender.
For those of average build,
mark 8.5 centimetres.
Measure the distance from the
hem mark to the collar base.
The front width measurement mark is
positioned towards the
front from the side mark.
Add 0.4 cm to the width and mark up to
the position of the captain's collar.
Next, connect the underlap position and
the collar-under dimension
position diagonally.
Next, mark the collar and shoulder area.
At the collar shoulder point, first
measure 3 centimetres from the ear tip,
Lightly mark 3 centimetres from the edge.
From the edge of the ear to 3
centimetres is 2 centimetres.
Mark 1.5 cm at a point
3 cm below the stop.
Mark a 0.3 cm point at the stop.
At the shoulder, 9.6 centimetres.
It ties with a beautiful curve.
At the underarm drop position, tie the 0.2
cm seam allowance above
the mark to the mark piece.
This completes the markings
around the collar and shoulders.
Intended for the centre back, with
the underlap positioned at the ro.
In this manner, the tape measure is
positioned to ensure accurate measurement.
This completes the marking
for the front panel.