Next is the marking of the lapel.
First, thread the fabric
through the hem opening.
Place the front facing fabric with its
pattern matched facing downwards, with the
left and right facings
right sides together.
Align the hem and the underside of the
collar, both cut through the
grain, and sew them together.
First, I shall record the severing from
the cut edge, noting both
civil and military affairs.
Next, mark 2 centimetres
for the foot allowance.
Mark the collar-to-hem measurement from
the 2-centimetre hem allowance, noting it
on the facing and the
underside of the collar.
Add a 1.5 cm seam
allowance at the neckline.
From this 1.5 cm mark, mark the width of
the lapel plus 0.2 cm
towards the inner side.
Measure the seam allowance for the
underlap at the collar-under
dimension position.
Add 2.5 cm to that measurement and mark
the hem allowance of
0.3 cm at the hem edge.
The hem of the lining is
fastened to the collar base.
Mark the 0.3 cm point at the front edge
and connect it diagonally
to the collar base position.
Measure precisely from the collar edge at
the top to the hem at the bottom
and make a note of the measurements.
This completes the marking of the lapel.