I shall now sew the sleeves.
Turn the cuff inside out and
spread it out towards you.
As sleeves become difficult to fold once
sewn into a circle, it is
advisable to sew the sleeves first.
Before putting them on, fold the
cuffs over three times first.
This is the cuff.
Place the folding iron against
the 6-millimetre seam allowance.
Open this 6 millimetre gap and
fold half of it, 3 millimetres.
Furthermore, the finished product
is a 3-millimetre tri-fold.
I'll place the folding iron here.
On the outer surface, a shallow
stitch is applied under the sleeve.
Pin the seam allowance at the cross of the
underarm and cuff, then pin the swing
allowance and underarm cross together.
Place a pin 3 millimetres from the cut
edge at the 1.5-fold position
of the pattern allowance.
Place a pin 2 centimetres from the rounded
sleeve edge and sew this
section with shallow stitches.
Before sewing, measure the approximate
dimensions and thread the
needle to avoid wastage.
Sew a shallow stitch 3
millimetres from the edge.
Begin and end your
stitching with a backstitch.
Fold the iron with a
2-millimetre seam allowance.
The sections not to be basted
should be turned up at an angle.
Turn it over and adjust
it to match the tweezers.
In this manner, the seam is concealed
within the 2 millimetres
of the Kise mountain.
The basting stitches stop at the cuff.
A pin at the midpoint of the
rounded mark below the cuff.
Pin the sleeve width and sleeve
length together at the cross.
Place a pin at the mark for the sleeve cap
curve, and another pin at the
midpoint of the sleeve width.
To begin sewing the hem, pass the
thread through the edge of the fabric.
Once you've sewn up to the rounded
sleeve, do the finishing stitches.
Backstitch one small stitch.
Sew the rounded sections with a needle.
I'll just pop over briefly.
Finish the curve with a backstitch.
Sew up to the cuff stop.
I shall perform the ritual
of offering incense.
At the cuff, turn back one stitch smaller.
Scoop diagonally to stop.
Open the cuff.
Ensure the thread is securely fastened.
Sew back 2 centimetres.
I will stop the ball.