Mark the curved hem allowance by turning
out the back sleeve and marking
three points 5mm above the curve.
Place the rounded mould and
make a straight spatula.
Mark another centimetre higher.
Apply the rounded mould and
perform the investment process.
At this point, the underarm is marked from
the position of the curve, and the cuff
side is marked up to where
it meets the edge of the ear.
The finishing of the curves shall be
done with two strands of sewing thread.
Sew with a 5-millimetre stitch.
However, sew back along the outer and
inner needles, aligning them,
1 millimetre from the edge.
At this point, allow a 4 to 5 centimetre
slack to make it easier
to tighten the thread.
For the second piece, sew with stitches
aligned as for the first piece, then
sew back 1 millimetre from the edge.
Place the front outer side facing upwards,
and apply a 2-millimetre
allowance to the underarm.
Leave a 1-millimetre seam allowance
on the front sleeve below the cuff.
Position the rounded shoulder
1mm in front of the rounded seam.
Enclose within the seam allowance
and secure with a basting stitch.
Pull the tightening thread
from the outer thread.
A 1-millimetre gap will be left.
Next, tighten the thread
that has been sewn back.
Similarly with the second thread.
Pull the fabric taut, gathering
it towards the centre.
Use the curling iron to shape the hair
into a rounded form without any sharp
angles, and flatten the tucks slightly.
Once the curve is even, secure the thread
used for shaping the curve with a knot.
Remove the rounded mould
and turn it inside out.
The underarm curve is trimmed to a
1-millimetre allowance, while the underarm
is trimmed to a 2-millimetre allowance and
finished with a hair-pinning technique.