Align the cut edges of the collar opening
and secure with pins, then align the cut
edges of the hem opening
and hold in place with pins.
Carefully stretch the fabric taut with
pins, then secure the centre with a pin
to ensure both sides of the body lie flat.
Furthermore, in the centre of that, we
proceed to pin it in place
using the pinning method.
Begin sewing by backstitching one stitch
from 4 millimetres above the
three-fold seam allowance.
Once you have sewn to the hem, remove the
needle and allow the thread
to breathe for a good while.
At the hem, turn with a small needle.
Sew up to the hem's standing edge.
Thread the needle and sew
back along the cut edge.
I will stop the ball.
Leave the shoulder pad attachment
area unstitched when double-stitching.
Sew from a point 2 to 3 millimetres
inside the ear to the base of the ear.
Press a flat iron along the
seam to remove any creases.
Next, the back seam.
Fold the white fabric
2mm to the left side.