Bleaching. Prepare twice the length of the
cotton fabric, plus 2 centimetres for the
shoulder width. Apply a serger
stitch to the cut edges.
Fold the shoulder pad lengthwise
in half and widthwise in half.
Pin the shoulder seam allowance at 7.8 cm.
I'll insert the scissors.
Widen the width and cut the
opening on the front side.
Place the iron on the centre back of the
shoulder pad, then align the body and
shoulder pad fabric at the
shoulder seam and autumn cut edge.
The seam allowance and
the basting stitches.
Align the centre back
of the shoulder pads.
Pin the fabric flat.
Place shoulder pads 2 centimetres
apart, 1 millimetre outside the seam.
Bring the needle out through
the fabric and close it.
The stock is threaded twice.
Sew only the seam allowances
of the body diagonally.
At this stage, use white lower
thread No. 30 for the binding thread.
Lay the body and shoulder pads flat with
the seams open, align the cut edges of the
collar and shoulder openings,
and secure with pins.
The shoulder pad sits 1.2 centimetres
inwards from the edge
of the body's side seam.
The finishing of the collar shoulder area
and sleeve attachment line is carried out
in the same manner as
for the vertical fabric.