Place the front and back side seams right
sides together and fold along the
finished line to create a crease.
Pin the markings for the armholes
and hem with basting stitches.
Pin the centre to ensure the
front and back panels lie flat,
Then, at its centre, you insert
a pin as part of the procedure.
As with the back seam, place one stitch at
the hem stand, turn back one stitch at the
hem peak, and sew
according to the markings.
Once you have stitched up to the
eighth notch, take a deep breath.
For the body's eight-hole
fastening, take one stitch smaller.
We will implement a
backflow prevention measure.
Press the seam flat with a flat iron to
remove any creases, then fold the seam
allowance 2mm onto the front panel.
From the hem to 4 centimetres
below the side seam
Place the basting pin 5 millimetres
to the outside of the seam.
Open the back panel.
Crease it with your fingertips.
I'll give you a hand.
Fold the top edge to
the mark as indicated.
Next, bring out the front side.
Three millimetres outside the side seam.
At 3-centimetre intervals.
Bring the needle through the
fold allowance on the back piece.
Press and stitch down to 4
centimetres below the hemline.
The fold line of the back panel was pinned
in place within a
2-millimetre fold allowance.
Next, to prevent the seam allowance from
catching, use the iron to smooth
out the edges of the body opening.
Turn the body right side out.
Fold the eight-fold section as indicated.
5 centimetres above the sleeve attachment
point, sleeve attachment seam allowance 5
Fold the millimetre markings, and this
time fold along the natural diagonal.
Continue selling 5
millimetres up to Katayama.
I will insert the pins.
Similarly, we shall offer 5
millimetres on the opposite side.
The intimidating mouth is as marked.
Turn it over and re-pin the right side.
At this point, lower the tension on
the Katayama while inserting the pin.
Place pins on the opposite
side in the same manner.
Next, lay the side seam flat on the table,
smooth out the seam allowance, and
open the armhole without gathering.
Pin the hem in place.
The side seam allowance is attached to the
body with a flat seam, ending at the
shoulder seam and the lower
part of the sleeve attachment.
One stitch must be made on the Katayama.
The hem is applied up to 6 centimetres
from the edge, but the hemline is
positioned 5 millimetres
inwards from the cut edge.
Secure the thread, then stitch every 6
centimetres, followed by attaching
the ears at 3-centimetre intervals.
At this point, secure the position
approximately 2 to 3
millimetres inside the ear.
When the thread runs out midway,
join the ends with a slipknot.
Hold the end of thread A in your left
hand, and with your right hand take the
connecting end of thread B,
passing it under thread A.
Cross them over, form a loop with the B
thread, placing the B thread end
below and the A thread tip above.
Pass the end of thread A through
the loop and hold it in place.
Tighten the thread and tie it off.