Place the front panel right side up and
spread it out, then layer the facing
with the right sides together.
Marking the fold lines on the
lapels makes them easier to sew.
Pin the hem edge of the facing seam
allowance, matching the 2cm allowance.
Align the underlap of the body with the
tip of the underlap and pin them together.
Pin the collar points together.
Furthermore, pin each
section at the midpoint.
Begin sewing the facing by threading the
needle through the hemline
cut edge, then at the hem peak
Using a needle, make one backstitch, sew
to the edge of the lapel,
and take a thread break.
After backstitching, sewing back along the
seam will make it stiff, so sew up at a
45-degree angle and secure with a knot.
Place the flat iron on the seam.
Place the iron 2 millimetres
from the back right edge.
Take care to ensure that excessive
gathering does not occur at the
collar-under measurement position.
Thus, a 2-millimetre
allowance was applied.
Turn it over.
To attach the ear flaps to the lapels.
Pin the facing fabric
flat with straight pins.
Attaching the ear 1 from the diagonal
mark on the lapel attachment.
Mark the ear holes from 3 centimetres
above the hem to 6
centimetres above the hem.
The hem stopper should be positioned
within the white hem allowance.