Look at the hem of the front.
Please take care not to
let the skirt ride up.
Turn the hem inside out.
Fold the hem back 2 centimetres and press.
Apply a 1-centimetre fold iron at
half the length of the hem allowance.
Fold it into thirds.
The corner of the toe.
A pin in the finished piece.
We pinned the front side at 1 point 5 cm.
Fold the corners diagonally with the iron.
I will arrange it neatly in the frame.
Hold the stem at its base, gripping the
three corners of the stem's white section.
Remove the needle from the tip angle.
Sew the hem, collar-edge
hem and three-needle stitch.
Insert the needle into the
inner corner of the frame.
Turn the fabric 180 degrees.
Sew the seam allowance of the outer fabric
and the undercollar in a single stitch.
This is called a return kick.
Return the needle to the white corner at
the hem and stitch at
1-centimetre intervals.
At this point, also bring the needle
stitching out at the
right edge of the lapel.
With the hem allowance 2mm short of the
edge, remove the needle and turn the hem
allowance 180 degrees towards the
opposite side before stitching it back.
In this manner, within each
2-millimetre ridge, a ridge is formed.
I'll make sure to stitch it
securely so it doesn't come apart.
Finish off the toe by turning back and
knitting to the end, then work the slanted
section over 3 stitches, bringing
the needle out at the toe corner.
Small knots were tied.
I will.
This bead stopper should be drawn into the
yellowish-white section
so that it remains hidden.
I will cut the thread.
The hemming is now complete.
Thus, within each 2-millimetre
ridge, the ridge must not collapse.
I'll make sure the stitches
are clearly visible.