Insert a cotton muslin interlining
into the neckline facing at the back.
Honour. Combining the centre of the Ishin
with the collar, place the collar flat on
the fabric from the centre of
the collar to the left and right.
Place the collar seam and the raw
edge together and secure with pins.
Stitch flat with 2-centimetre
intervals between stitches.
Spread the collar fabric flat from the
shoulder seam to the tip of the collar.
At this point, take care to ensure there
are no creases in the collar cloth.
Place the collar, the collar stand, the
front edge seam allowance, and the
front panel seam allowance on top.
A slackness will form in the front panel,
centred around the tip of the blade, so
ensure it is fully stretched out here.
Fold the collar width
to the finished width.
Then apply the iron.
At this point, take
care not to stretch it.
Through the fabric at the collar tip.
Attaching the collar. Fold the undercollar
over the seam allowance by 2
millimetres and secure with pins.
Pin the collar in place with a dress pin,
securing the collar shoulder opening
position and the tip position.
Secure the middle section with a pin.
Do the same for the left half.
Next, fasten the collar points.
The collar edge is folded straight along
the finished grain line to set the crease.
Secure with a single
strand of sewing thread.
Bring the needle out from
the fold at the front collar.
Along the folded edge beneath the collar.
When you fold down the
collar side's fold line.
Scoop towards the three collar points.
Return to the front
collar's seam allowance.
Join the end of the thread.
Adjust to a length of 2 centimetres.
Twist the thread tightly to prevent the
knot from loosening, then join the two
strands together and twist
them in the opposite direction.
Pull the collar seam allowance out from
the stitching side to
reveal the inner collar.
Fold the front collar seam allowance and
pin it in place; spread out the back
collar seam allowance and pin it in place.
Sew 5 millimetres from the fold.
Backstitch from the first
stitch to the second.
I will stop the ball.
Fold the collar seam allowance
towards the inner side of the collar.
Pull up the collar seam
allowance diagonally like this.
Ensure the seam allowance does
not fold over to the AREA.
Enclose the collar seam allowance
with the undercollar and close it.
At this point, take care to ensure
no stitches show on the front collar.
Bring out the front collar.
The collar points are trimmed
to match the hairline.
Attach the back collar to the neckline
seam with a 2-millimetre
overlap, securing it with pins.
Bring the needle up one stitch above
the collar tip on the back collar.
The seam on the collar attachment side and
the underside of the
collar are folded over.
Sew the inside edge with 6mm stitches.
Take care to sew so that no white
stitches show on the front collar.