Ensure the left and right sleeves are not
mixed up, and verify the sleeve attachment
measurements on the body and
the sleeve from the front.
Wrap the sleeves within the body piece
and align them right sides together.
Examine the sleeve fabric
and attach the sleeve.
Pin the sleeve cap to the
side seam of the body.
Well.
Next, align the sleeve attachment
points and secure them with pins.
At this point, pin the body piece
to the folded mountain edge.
Place a pin 5 centimetres above the sleeve
attachment point, aligned with
the 5-millimetre seam allowance.
Continue to place pins at 5cm intervals.
Similarly, place a pin at
the beginning of the month.
Sleeve attachment. First, remove the
basting pins and use a small needle
to take a small horizontal stitch.
I shall stop.
Next, we perform the scoop stop.
When starting to attach,
sew with a 2.5 cm hem.
Sew up to one stitch before
the end and remove the needle.
Sew the outer mountain with a
three-and-a-half-stitch backstitch.
Sew the other side in the same manner,
then remove the needle 2cm from the
end and sew back along the same path.
The sleeve attachment shall
be secured with a slip stitch.
That completes the external connection.
In this manner, the body side
is stitched with shallow folds.
Place the flat iron on the outside.
A 2-millimetre restriction will
be applied to the sleeve side.
Turn up the sleeves.
Trim the 2mm ridge and
finish with a finishing tool.
Next, fold the lower edge of
the kuke-dai as indicated.
At this point, please take care to include
the seam allowance under the
sleeve within the front sleeve.
Turn the swing side out and neaten
the sleeve attachment seam allowance.
First, attach three pin tacks
centred on the sleeve cap.
Next, pin the underarm gusset in
place to prevent it from bunching up.
Pin the sleeve to the sleeve stop.
Next, attach the ear 3
centimetres above the sleeve stop.
Attach one stitch to
the sleeve hem as well.
Furthermore, within the 2mm seam allowance
at the underarm, the needle stitches
for the ear hair are visible.
In this manner, secure one stitch within
the 2mm seam allowance
of the underarm yoke.
The finishing iron is used to shape the
rounded underarm area of the furisode
sleeves, and to adjust the
cuffs and the kise mountain.