Arrange the household stock, dress from
the front collar side,
and press the mountain.
Attach a straightening thread to the back
corner of the household fabric and finish
it at a right angle, then
iron the entire collar.
Iron the entire garment, including the
back of the collar, to
complete the finish.
Next, iron from the
collar down to the toes.
Attach a basting thread to the corner of
the hem, then finish the entire
hem with a pressing iron.
Please pull the thread at the toe
corner to form a right angle as shown.
Iron the right lapel.
Show your face.
Remove fine lines throughout.
Press the creases and iron the garment.
Iron the shoulder area from the right
side with the back piece folded over.
Finally, please remove
the finishing thread.
For folding creases, the back seam
should be on the right side panel. 4
Press down firmly and fold to create a
crease right up to the edge of the collar.
The side seam is dropped 4mm from the back
panel side, and a fold is made
up to the edge of the armhole.
Turn the facing outwards and fold it
towards the front panel, 4mm in from the
seam, up to the collar base position.
The other one likewise.
I will crease it.